<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ruby on Honza Pokorny</title>
    <link>https://honza.ca/categories/ruby/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ruby on Honza Pokorny</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 20:20:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://honza.ca/categories/ruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I don&#39;t like the Ruby community</title>
      <link>https://honza.ca/2011/06/why-i-dont-like-the-ruby-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 20:20:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://honza.ca/2011/06/why-i-dont-like-the-ruby-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I write Python and Javascript code. I use Django and jQuery. And I cringe every
time I have to run &lt;code&gt;gem install x&lt;/code&gt;. I only have a limited understanding of
Ruby and hardly any of Ruby on Rails. It seems disorganized to me and hard to
process. All this is fine &amp;ndash; I don&amp;rsquo;t have to use any of it if I don&amp;rsquo;t like it,
right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always knew there was something wrong with the way Ruby works. I don&amp;rsquo;t mean
wrong like murdering children, I just mean wrong like I don&amp;rsquo;t know why things
are the way they are. There are a lot of talented Ruby programmers and I don&amp;rsquo;t
mean to dismiss that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, though, I came across a tweet that I made me realize what it was that
I didn&amp;rsquo;t like about Ruby. It was like a small revelation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markup is markup, not Ruby. JavaScript is JavaScript, not Ruby. CSS is CSS,
not Ruby. Get that in your head before I slap you. - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/ara%5Fp/status/81425173965832193&#34;&gt;@ara_p&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you get it? &lt;a href=&#34;http://ruby-doc.org/stdlib/libdoc/erb/rdoc/classes/ERB.html&#34;&gt;ERB&lt;/a&gt; is Ruby with some html-like fragments mixed in.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://jashkenas.github.com/coffee-script/&#34;&gt;CoffeeScript&lt;/a&gt; is a Ruby-like language that compiles to Javascript. &lt;a href=&#34;http://sass-lang.com/&#34;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt; is
a Ruby-like language for writing css files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you know it, everything will be in Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
