<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>random on Honza Pokorny</title>
    <link>https://honza.ca/categories/random/</link>
    <description>Recent content in random on Honza Pokorny</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 10:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://honza.ca/categories/random/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a blog?</title>
      <link>https://honza.ca/2011/07/what-is-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 10:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://honza.ca/2011/07/what-is-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have noticed that many people don&amp;rsquo;t know what a blog is, so I would like to
talk about that briefly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A blog is a type of website or part of a website. Blogs are usually
maintained by an individual with regular entries. (&amp;hellip;) Entries are
commonly displayed in reverse-chronological order. Blog can also be used as
a verb, meaning to maintain or add content to a blog. Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blog&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A blog is a website. A blog has many &lt;em&gt;entries&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;posts&lt;/em&gt;. To write a post
means to update your existing blog with a new article. To create or write a new
blog means to start a new website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please, don&amp;rsquo;t say that you are going write a blog when you mean you will write
a post. That would be wrong. OK?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Money Is Made Online</title>
      <link>https://honza.ca/2010/12/how-money-is-made-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 21:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://honza.ca/2010/12/how-money-is-made-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My friends of the non-geek type often ask me how companies like Facebook can
make so much money and provide their service for free at the same time. Here is
a quick example of how you can make money online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warning: this is a not a get rich quick scheme. I&amp;rsquo;m not going teach you how to
make millions working for Google from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently started following John Gruber&amp;rsquo;s blog &lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net/&#34;&gt;Darring Fireball&lt;/a&gt;. This
gentleman seems to be rather influential in the hacker community. On the
website, he says that there are more than 400,000 subscribers that frequently
read his blog. In the world of Internet publishing, this is a great deal of
exposure. Not very many people get this much attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you browse through the site, you will soon notice that you can sponsor John
to write more articles. You can pay him $5,000/month - in return, a small
banner with your company&amp;rsquo;s advertising graphics will be displayed in a
prominent place on John&amp;rsquo;s blog for that month. You will get millions of people
every month looking at your ad for just $5,000/month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing interesting articles about the web is a full-time job for John.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
