<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Android on Honza Pokorny</title>
    <link>https://honza.ca/categories/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Android on Honza Pokorny</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 22:24:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://honza.ca/categories/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Nokia chose Windows over Android</title>
      <link>https://honza.ca/2011/02/why-nokia-chose-windows-over-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 22:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://honza.ca/2011/02/why-nokia-chose-windows-over-android/</guid>
      <description>Today, we have all heard about the new deal struck between Nokia and Microsoft. It is a major change in Nokia&amp;rsquo;s strategy which will without a doubt affect the smartphone market.
A few month ago, the Executive Vice President of Nokia announced that switching to Android is like peeing in your boots for warmth. Well, let me say this: if switching to Android is like peeing in your boots, switching to Windows is like shitting your pants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Chose Android</title>
      <link>https://honza.ca/2010/11/why-i-chose-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2010 22:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://honza.ca/2010/11/why-i-chose-android/</guid>
      <description>Recently, we have heard that the Android operating system has the largest market share in the US, and is set to take over the whole world. Personally, I chose Android long before it was this popular. Why?
Background I won&amp;rsquo;t bore you with my personal history, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to say a few things. I&amp;rsquo;m a programmer and like to tweet things. If there isn&amp;rsquo;t an application that does the job, I write it myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Use Twitter OAuth On Android</title>
      <link>https://honza.ca/2010/09/how-to-use-twitter-oauth-on-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 22:31:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://honza.ca/2010/09/how-to-use-twitter-oauth-on-android/</guid>
      <description>If you are developing an application for the Android platform, and you need to interact with the Twitter API, you now have to use OAuth to authenticate the user. In this article, we will have a look on how you can do that.
What is OAuth? OAuth is a way of accessing a user&amp;rsquo;s data (e.g. tweets) without asking for the user&amp;rsquo;s username and password. Your application opens the Twitter website which will ask the user if they want to allow you to access their data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>