<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bibles on Honza Pokorny</title>
    <link>https://honza.ca/categories/bibles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bibles on Honza Pokorny</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 10:14:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://honza.ca/categories/bibles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>If novels were formatted like bibles</title>
      <link>https://honza.ca/2019/01/if-novels-were-formatted-like-bibles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 10:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://honza.ca/2019/01/if-novels-were-formatted-like-bibles/</guid>
      <description>Bibles are notorious for being cluttered with all kinds of content besides the actual Word of God. Here is a list of common things:
 Chapter numbers Verse numbers Chapter headings Translation footnotes Cross-references (in the text, and in the center column) Chain references Pilcrows  The traditional setting also includes things like:
 Double column Verse-by-verse setting (where each verse starts on a new line) Words in italics Pronunciation marks  While these tools might be helpful for study, they certain don&amp;rsquo;t help with fluency in reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My journey to find the best Bible</title>
      <link>https://honza.ca/2017/11/my-journey-to-find-the-best-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 13:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://honza.ca/2017/11/my-journey-to-find-the-best-bible/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; or, ESV Pitt Minion in black goatskin review
I have been reading Mark Bertrand&amp;rsquo;s Bible Design Blog for a few years now. Through his long-form writing, I have come to appreciate beautiful typography, fine craftsmanship, single-column layouts, and attention to detail in modern Bible-making. I even helped him with a website update several years ago.
For the longest time, though, my reading was just that&amp;mdash;reading. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine spending so much money on a single Bible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>