<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rant on Honza Pokorny</title>
    <link>https://honza.ca/categories/rant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rant on Honza Pokorny</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 11:25:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://honza.ca/categories/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Language choice</title>
      <link>https://honza.ca/2015/11/language-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 11:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://honza.ca/2015/11/language-choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warning: this is a rant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have made great progress in my journey towards Haskell
enlightenment. I finally see how many of the little pieces of the Haskell
puzzle fit together. At this point, I feel empowered to go forth and write
useful programs. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/%5Fhonza/status/660421406698508288&#34;&gt;read&lt;/a&gt; through the source of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/scotty-web/scotty&#34;&gt;Scotty&lt;/a&gt; the web framework
the other day, and I was very pleasantly surprised that I understood how it
works. I absolutely &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; Haskell. I love that it makes you think. One does
not simply open a text editor and start banging at the keyboard to write a
Haskell program. I love that Haskell encourages generalizations and
abstractions. One of the biggest heureka moments in my journey was
understanding the full implications of why a function of type &lt;code&gt;a -&amp;gt; a&lt;/code&gt; has a
single implementation. I&amp;rsquo;m addicted to running my program for the first time
(after fighting with the compiler for ages), and having it work. I think monad
transformers and lenses are really clever. By many criteria, Haskell is the
perfect programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has taken me four years to get here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to get so discouraged that I took breaks for weeks or months at a time
because I didn&amp;rsquo;t see the point of continuing. But I always came back. Now I
have finally arrived. I would say I&amp;rsquo;m an intermediate Haskeller. Naturally,
I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about writing some Haskell code at work which is going to be easy
given our service-oriented architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also been playing with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.purescript.org/&#34;&gt;Purescript&lt;/a&gt; which is a Haskell dialect that
compiles to javascript. In many ways, Purescript is a much better Haskell
because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come with the historical baggage. In speaking with my
colleague who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know Purescript about introducing it into our code base,
I realized the gravity of what I was asking him to learn. It sounds great to
say &amp;ldquo;let&amp;rsquo;s rewrite this in purescript&amp;rdquo; and expect someone to come back from
their weekend having learned enough to be dangerous when it took me four years
to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another great example is the open source community. If you choose Haskell for
your open source project, you might be productive, safe to refactor, write
little code &amp;mdash; but how many people will be willing to learn Haskell to
contribute a fix or a new feature?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of my Haskell friends like to mock the &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; programming language. Myself
included at times. Mind you, the language is &lt;em&gt;objectively&lt;/em&gt; poorly designed.
The error handling, the lack of generics, the ridiculous package manager, the
absurd type system, the &lt;code&gt;range&lt;/code&gt; thing, etc. It&amp;rsquo;s almost exactly the opposite
of Haskell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, Go is a lot &lt;a href=&#34;http://adambard.com/blog/top-github-languages-2014/&#34;&gt;more popular&lt;/a&gt; than Haskell according to GitHub. Yet,
there are so many amazing projects written in Go, like Docker, Influxdb, etcd,
consul, prometheus, packer, and many more. Unlike Haskell, if you ask your
coworkers to learn Go over the weekend, everyone will come back with a little
app they built. A clearly inferior tool is used by crowds of people to build
cool things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What should we conclude from this? The choice of programming language matters.
Programming is a social activity. Fewer features seems to equal easier to
learn. Generalization and programming language innovation seem to be out of
favor. Creating software to solve real problems with blunt tools seems to be a
lot more important than using a sharp axe. We&amp;rsquo;d much rather use an inferior
tool whose manual we don&amp;rsquo;t have to read. We&amp;rsquo;d much rather snap a picture
with our smartphone than to learn how to use a DSLR.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International families</title>
      <link>https://honza.ca/2013/04/international-families/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 14:10:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://honza.ca/2013/04/international-families/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m from the Czech republic. My wife is from Canada. We got married in
Canada. Our son was born in the United Kingdom. Our daughter was born in
Canada. Both of our children are by birth Czech and Canadian at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want our children to be able to prove both of those citizenships and the
following is the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-son&#34;&gt;Our son&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our son Wyatt was born in the UK. He has a British birth certificate but is
not a British citizen. In order to travel out of the UK, he had to get a
passport. Because we now live in Canada, we decided it would make more sense
to get the Canadian one done first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for someone without a Canadian birth certificate to get a Canadian
passport, you need to get a proof of citizenship. This is a piece of paper
that Wyatt will have to use for the rest of his life to prove his Canadian
citizenship instead of a birth certificate like all normal Canadians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to get a passport, you first need a proof of citizenship. Wyatt is a
Canadian citizen because his mother is Canadian. In order to get the proof of
citizenship, you need to send a superlegalized British birth certificate to the
Canadian government and include the mother&amp;rsquo;s birth certificate to prove the she
is Canadian. Super what? Superlegalization is a process whereby Canada and
the UK agree to authorize the use of each other&amp;rsquo;s legal documents. Wyatt&amp;rsquo;s
British birth certificate must be stamped by a Canadian embassy in the UK to
say that this is in fact a legal document issued by the United Kingdom. Also,
along with his application we had to send in our marriage certificate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once he&amp;rsquo;s obtained the proof of citizenship, we can apply for a passport.
Fortunately, the Canadian government is nice enough to allow you to apply for
the proof of citizenship and the passport on one application. We had his
passport in a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we are living in Canada and want to get him all the papers he needs to be a
true Czech citizen. This means that we need to have his British birth
certificate legalized by the UK, then translated into Czech by a
government-approved translator, then approved by the Ministry of Interior of
the Czech republic and then we can apply for a Czech birth certificate. Of
course, the application requires us to send in our marriage certificate. Since
we got married in Canada, we have a Canadian marriage certificate. This means
that we need to have to superlegalized, translated into Czech and approved by
the Ministry. More fees and translators aren&amp;rsquo;t cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once he has a Czech birth certificate, he needs to apply for a birth number
which isn&amp;rsquo;t unlike a social security number except it&amp;rsquo;s derived from your date
of birth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-daughter&#34;&gt;Our daughter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our daughter Eliška was born in Canada. This means she can fortunately get a
Canadian passport without any issues. She is a real Canadian like most people
and doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to have any special paperwork to prove that she is. Piece of
cake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the Czech side of things, it&amp;rsquo;s seems it&amp;rsquo;s much more
complicated than with our son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, she needs to apply for a proof of Czech citizenship. Her Canadian birth
certificate needs to be superlegalized, translated and approved. This is
fortunately done at the Czech embassy in Ottawa and you are allowed to
translate the document yourself and they will verify it for you. One of the
forms that you need to send in with the application requires you to have your
signature verified by a notary. No big deal, right? Well, good luck finding a
notary in Canada who speaks Czech and is willing to notarize your signature. I
was emailing back and forth with the embassy that they allowed me to photocopy
my ID and take that to the notary instead. I&amp;rsquo;ll sign it in front of him and he
can verify my identity and signature. I&amp;rsquo;ll send this in along with the
application. The application process takes about 4-6 months according to their
website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have yet to apply for this. But when it comes back, we will have to apply
for a Czech birth certificate and a birth number. More forms, more fees, more
superlegalization, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter what you do, do not romanticize international families. It&amp;rsquo;s not all
that fun all the time&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
